And today, I'll be talking to you about developing your plot.
So, during this series, we've gone over the plot.
You start at the beginning, we've established the status quo, just where everything starts in the beginning of the play.
Also, noting that the status quo is not the beginning of time, things will have happened before the status quo.
We've gone over the inciting incident, the thing that jumps starts the action of the play.
We've gone over the hook, the act one hook.
We've gone over the payoff in act two and how things are foreshadowed in act one.
And we've gone over the climax, the highest point of action in the play and the resolution leading to the end.
These are the elements of a plot of the play.
A play moves in a forward progression towards its ending.
Options become lower.
People try different tactics to get what they want and strong objectives.
People are willing to die for whatever they want.
Its high stakes, the highest stakes you can possibly make or what would make a good drama.
And so, this is the chart that makes our course.
Also starting with the ending, moving backwards as a way to try to understand how to incorporate elements of foreshadowing, of setting things up and paying them off, of creating hooks and creating dramatic situations and this is the fundamental of plot.